quartzy.com 2010-07-05

# Quartzy privacy policies

## Privacy Policy

Date of Last Revision: December 23rd, 2008 

#### Introduction:

Welcome to Quartzy, a networking site for life-scientists that connects you to you other scientists and provides tools enabling you to be more efficient in your lab. The Quartzy service and network (collectively, "Quartzy" or "the Service" or "the Company") are operated by Quartzy, LLC. By accessing or using our web site at [www.quartzy.com](https://www.quartzy.com/ "www.quartzy.com"), you (the "User") signify that you have read, understand and agree to be bound by the (1) Terms of Use ("Terms of Use" or "Agreement") and (2) The Quartzy Privacy Policy, whether or not you are a registered member of Quartzy. This document explains how Quartzy uses the information you as a Quartzy Member ("user") provide. 

We at Quartzy are committed to respecting your privacy, while providing you with a platform to share information with your colleagues. In this document we also explain the safeguards that have been put into place to protect the information you provide us. If you do not accept either the Terms of Use or the Privacy Policy you should not become a Quartzy member and you should not access the website. 

#### Information Collected by Quartzy:

Quartzy collects two different types of information from you: 

  1. Information that you choose to enter such as your name, experience, educational background, relationships with other Quartzy users, publications, technical skills, and reagent inventory. Both Personal Data and Professional Data (both are defined below) fall into this category.
  2. Information about how you use the website. 
    1. We collect basic information such as your IP address, the browser you are using to access Quartzy, and the operating system running on your computer. 
    2. We also track what website software features you access, how often you access them, and how active you are when you access them. Knowing this information allows us to improve the site and make it better fit the needs of Quartzy users. 
    3. Quartzy also uses "cookies". Cookies are small amounts of data that are stored on your computer and relay to the website your usage patterns. They allow personalization of the website. You can block cookies through your web browser if you do not want Quartzy to use cookies.

"Personal Data" is defined as any information you provide to Quartzy about you, including but not limited to your full name, picture, email address, institutional affiliation, mailing address, experience, publications and laboratory address. 

"Professional Data" is defined as any information you provide to Quartzy about your research, including but not limited to certain details of your reagent inventory, protocols, animals, equipment, facilities, or ongoing experiments.

By joining Quartzy, you accept this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use; however, as a Quartzy user you are under no obligation to provide Personal Data or Professional Data to Quartzy.

#### Registration:

Only current or past research scientists should register with Quartzy. Membership is void where prohibited. You agree to the Terms of Use and to this Privacy Policy on registration. Some Personal Data is required for registration. If you do not wish to provide Quartzy with this Personal Data, you should not register on the website. Upon successful registration your Personal Data will be cross-referenced with available public databases to determine whether to activate your account. Quartzy may collect information about you from other sources such as university databases, search engines, newspapers and others for the purposes of identity verification and account activation. Upon successful account activation your email address will serve as your username and you will use the password you created on registration to log-in to the website. While you are a Quartzy user you agree to the following:

  1. The Personal Data you provide will be accurate, truthful, complete, and current.
  2. The Professional Data you provide will be accurate, truthful, complete, and current.
  3. You will maintain the security of your password
  4. You will update the Registration Information and Personal Data you provide to Quartzy as it changes.
  5. You are fully responsible for all use and content of your account and for any actions that occur using your account.

Registration, use of, or access to the website by people under eighteen (18) years of age is in violation of this Privacy Policy and in violation of the Terms of Use. By registering with Quartzy, you represent and warrant that you are 18 years of age or older and that you agree to and will comply with all of the terms of this Privacy Policy and all the terms in the Terms of Use.

Quartzy reserves the right to terminate user membership at any time with or without cause.

#### How Quartzy Uses Your Information:

Quartzy uses your Personal Data and your Professional Data to contact you regarding: your account, changes to the website, website newsletters, and special offers open to Quartzy users. You may opt-out of these communications if you so choose by contacting us at [admin@quartzy.com](mailto:admin@quartzy.com "admin@quartzy.com"). Should you opt-out, Quartzy reserves the right to send you notices regarding the status of your account. Quartzy may use Personal Data to contact you, and may also enhance or merge Personal Data with data obtained from other parties for the same purposes.

At times, Quartzy will collect, retain, and use your Personal Data for market analysis. Quartzy may also compile and distribute reports to third parties using Personal Data and Professional Data; however, individuals will never be identified in these reports.

Quartzy may keep a backup copy of all Personal Data and Professional Data for a reasonable period of time to allow the website and its users to revert back to a prior version of that Data.

#### Personal and Professional Data Sharing

Quartzy users can control the privacy settings of their Personal Data and their Professional Data. Quartzy users may, at any point, modify their privacy settings. You should understand that no security measures are perfect or inviolable, and while Quartzy makes reasonable effort to preserve the integrity of the privacy structure on the website, you post Personal Data and Professional Data at your own risk. Quartzy is not responsible for circumvention of any of our privacy settings. Quartzy cannot guarantee that the Data you submit to the website will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. In the event of a security breach we will notify the affected users and repair the breach in a reasonable amount of time.

Certain aspects of your Professional Data are viewable on Quartzy only by you, certain aspects of your Professional Data are viewable on Quartzy by users you to whom you designate access, and certain aspects of your Professional Data are viewable by all Quartzy users. The extent of data shared is specified by the relationships you have with other users as defined in the Terms of Use. Your Personal data is intended to reflect your research activities and past experience and is by default viewable by both Quartzy members and the general public. Users may elect to restrict access to their personal data to Quartzy members only, and they may exclude their personal email address from all Quartzy users. Relationship definitions do not affect access to Personal Data. Personal data will appear in Quartzy-restricted search results, and may be made available to third party search engines. We do not sell, trade, rent, or otherwise disclose your Personal Data or your Professional Data, other than as stated in this Privacy Policy and in the Terms of Use, unless you have given us written or electronically transmitted permission to do so. 

Quartzy recognizes that some Personal and Professional Data is proprietary or otherwise sensitive, and has developed privacy settings to restrict access to these Data. For example, reagents can be stored in user-generated "Private Inventories". When a reagent is placed in a user's private inventory only he or she can see that reagent, and it is not shared among his or her labmates. Users can make adjustments to these privacy settings at any time.

Quartzy works with other companies to provide information technology services to its users. These companies may have access to Quartzy's databases, but only for the purposes of providing service to Quartzy. For example, a third party may obtain access to your Personal or Professional Data in an effort to update database software, or manage data. These companies will operate under consumer confidentiality agreements with Quartzy. 

Users should report any unauthorized activity or unauthorized use of information to [admin@quartzy.com](mailto:admin@quartzy.com "admin@quartzy.com") as soon as they become aware of such activity. Unauthorized use of User Personal and Professional data violates this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use.

#### Invitations

If you choose to use our invitation service, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as a colleague's email address. We will automatically send your colleague an email inviting him or her to visit the site. Quartzy stores this information to send this invitation, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [admin@quartzy.com](mailto:admin@quartzy.com "admin@quartzy.com") to request that we remove this information from our database.

#### Changes to Business

Quartzy may transfer, sell, or assign information concerning users' use of the site, including without limitation, users' Personal Data and Professional Data, in the event of a change in business practices such as a merger, acquisition by another company, consolidation, liquidation, or reorganization. If such an event threatens to change the manner in which users' Personal Data and Professional Data are handled, they will be notified of such a change and be given the option to delete their account prior to such an event.

#### Changes to Policies

Quartzy reserves the right to revise or update this policy at any time. If we do so, we will post a new Privacy Policy on the site and/or notify you. We encourage our users to check back frequently for changes. This Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use apply to the Quartzy alpha version and to all subsequent versions. 

You may contact us at any time with questions or concerns regarding the Terms of Use or the Privacy Policy at [admin@quartzy.com](mailto:admin@quartzy.com "admin@quartzy.com").
